Allan Raymart C. Paraiso

+639383025631· allanraymart.paraiso@g.msuiit.edu.ph · github.com/YeXiu2001 Santo Nino, Pagadian City, Zamboanga del Sur Web Portfolio: https://raymart-paradise.vercel.app

SUMMARY

I am a graduate of Bachelor's Degree in Information Technology major in Database Systems as Magna Cum Laude, at Mindanao State University - Iligan Institute of Technology (MSU-IIT). I have been the sole developer for most of my college system projects, and as well as my internship project. Up to date I already worked with 3 companies as part time or as an independent contractee.

NOTABLE PROJECTS

Laundry Cashflow and Management System

Full Stack Developer

Laundry Cashflow and Management System is a web-based application made with **Vanilla PHP for back-end development**, **HTML**, **CSS Bootstrap 5**, **and Javascript** for the Front-end, **PostgreSQL** for the database management, and **ChartJS** for data visualization. The main features of this system are sales and expenses management module, and employee management module.

Userfeedback, Complaint, Whistleblower Module Full Stack Developer

The project is a proposed module or sub-system for the MSU-IIT National Multi-Purpose Cooperative. This subsystem is made with **PHP - Laravel 10** for the back-end development, **HTML, CSS -LTEADMIN, Javascript, and ChartJS for the front-end development**, and **MySQL** for database management. The main features of this subsystem are userfeedback, whistleblower and complaint reporting, and managing reports.

LigtasGIS: Web-Based Emergency Reporting GIS Application Full Stack Developer

LigtasGIS is my capstone project aimed to provide a platform for emergency reporting employing real-time communication between pages, and aligned my development in accordance with the SDLC: Prototype Model. The system is made with PHP - Laravel 10 and Laravel Spatie for back-end development, HTML, CSS, Jquery - AJAX for front-end development, PusherJS and Laravel Echo for websocket implementation, LeafletJS and OSRM for the mapping features, and MySQL database management. The main features of this system is the reporting module for the user - citizens, and report and user management for the user - admin, and reatime monitoring for user-rescuers

Dynamic Queueing System

Full Stack Developer

The Dynamic Queueing System as a web-based application assigned to me during my internship, The system is made with PHP - Laravel 10 and Laravel Spatie for back-end development, HTML, CSS, JQuery - AJAX for front-end development, PusherJS and Laravel Echo for the realtime implementation, and MySQL for database management. The main features of this system are the dynamic user and window management.

Cirrhosis Patient Survival Rate using Machine Learning Algorithm Full Stack Developer

The project is a web-based application aimed to use machine learning algorithm specifically Random Forest Classifier and Regression models, the development of the system is in accordance with the SDLC: Rapid Application Development (RAD) methodology. As a prerequisite to the development of the application, a historical data is acquired and cleaned then used to train the models using RFC and Regression using Python. For the web-based application Python-Flask is used for the back-end development and API integration from the trained models, HTML, CSS – Bootstrap 5, ChartJS, and Javascript are used for frontend development

WORK EXPERIENCE

Assistant Project Manager I Smartbyte Solutions

October 2024 - November

Meta and Tiktok Ads API and Data Integration

This project aims to utilize Meta and Tiktok ads API to monitor advertisement metrics. As an Assistant Project Manager and Lead Developer role, I made a documentation for the first two modules of the project, and was closely working with a team member. The tech stack for this project is Vanilla **PHP** for the backend development, **HTML CSS-Bootsrap 5**, **Javascript**, **JQuery** - **AJAX**, and **MySQL**. I parted ways with the company since they haven't paid me and isn't communicating with me regarding my compensation.

Junior Web Developer (Project Based) | Perzeus Corp

July 2024 - Present

CEOMIS

I worked with a Senior Developer in improving their current system for the Local Government. Since the system is already completed, I am primarily tasked to test the system for any potential bugs or errors, and as well as communicating with the employees of the LGU that uses the system. This company currently aims to provide services to the Local Government Unit only thus I haven't been a part of a new project yet.

Junior Web Developer (Part time) I Pixzel Digital

May 14, 2024 - Present

BizSmart Resto

BizSmart Resto is a project for a client, the system aimed to streamline the processes within the resto business which includes menu, POS, and inventory. I am primarily assigned to several modules which includes Menu Engineering, Items registration, and Products registration, and as well as making and handling API. The web-based system is made with PHP - Laravel 10 for the back-end development, HTML, CSS - Bootstrap 5, JQuery AJAX for the front-end development and MySQL for the database. Vanilla - PHP is also used for the Menu/POS

Supervised On The Job Training | Pixzel Digital

January 29 - May 12 2024

Junior Full-Stack Web Developer

During the internship, I was assigned a project - Dynamic Queueing System, a web-based application deployable to any institution that requires it due to its dynamic features ensured in its development. My role is developing the project in its entirety, initially I set up the database using **MySQL** based on the specifications from my Senior Developer, **PHP Laravel 10** is used for back-end development, and **HTML**, **CSS**, **JQuery - AJAX** are used for front-end development.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology (Magna Cum Laude)

2020-2024

College of Computer Studies

Mindanao State University - Iligan Institute of Technology

Iligan City, Lanao del Norte 9200

Grade 7 - Grade 12 (With Honors)

2014-2020

Pagadian City Science High School Pagadian City, Zamboanga del Sur

Grade 1 - Grade 6 (Academic Excellence Awardee)

2014-2020

Pagadian City Science High School

Pagadian City, Zamboanga del Sur

BACKGROUND IN PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

- PHP
- PHP Laravel 10
- Python
- Python Flask
- HTML
- CSS Bootstrap 5
- Javascript
- MYSQL
- POSTGRESQL
- NOSQL (Firebase)
- Git (Version Control)
- Postman (for API)

CHARACTER REFERENCES

Neschelle Joy Villasurda Bramida

Pixzel Digital - Managing Director 0906 505 6432

pixzeldigital@gmail.com

Rigo Millares

 $\label{eq:conditional} \mbox{Perzeus Corp - CEO and Founder}$

0917 702 8167